<h1>Project Overview</h1><p>The purpose of this project is to design and implement a centralized CRM system that supports lead management, project coordination, task tracking, stakeholder communication, and workflow automation across multiple business verticals. The CRM will enable seamless conversion of leads into structured projects, coordinate with internal and external collaborators (such as architects and PMCs), and ensure all operations are traceable, measurable, and securely managed.</p><h1><a id="_heading=h.4lda39jq9zbg"></a>Objective </h1><ul><li>Enable centralized lead capturing and conversion into structured projects.</li><li>Standardize project workflows, including templates for architect-driven processes.</li><li>Automate task creation, reminders, and escalations to improve accountability.</li><li>Provide real-time dashboards for project health, task progress, and user performance.</li><li>Maintain centralized documentation and communication history per project.</li><li>Implement robust access control for internal teams and external stakeholders.</li><li>Ensure activity traceability via detailed audit trails and logs.</li></ul><h1><a id="_heading=h.86v2hnoydq8g"></a>Scope features</h1><h2><a id="_heading=h.4y9b1ackt5zi"></a>Lead Management</h2><ul><li>Design lead intake forms with required fields (source, contact, category).</li><li>Implement a status-based lead pipeline with automatic project conversion on qualification.</li><li>Enable dashboards and filters to track lead performance and conversion ratios.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.s19lhi9uim4h"></a>Project Management</h2><ul><li>Auto-generate project workspaces linked to converted leads.</li><li>Implement architect-specific workflow templates when applicable.</li><li>Provide visual project timelines, phase tracking, and milestone updates.</li><li>Integrate a real-time project dashboard for management overview.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.xn0g335mlib3"></a>Task Management</h2><ul><li>Create task and subtask structures with assignment, deadlines, and priority settings.</li><li>Enable Kanban, calendar, and Gantt views for flexible project visualization.</li><li>Automate reminders, alerts, and escalations for overdue tasks.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.w9k6dswma4co"></a>Contact &amp; Stakeholder Management</h2><ul><li>Centralize contact database for individuals, architects, PMCs, and vendors.</li><li>Link contacts to projects and assign roles with specific access levels.</li><li>Enable secure collaboration for external stakeholders with view/comment/upload permissions.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.vjj0rnpahycx"></a>Document &amp; File Management</h2><ul><li>Enable per-project document uploads categorized by type (Designs, Contracts, Invoices).</li><li>Support version control for key documents.</li><li>Provide document previews and search functionality.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.zdxgzc7t32m4"></a>Workflow Automation</h2><ul><li>Implement event-based automation (e.g., lead conversion triggers project creation).</li><li>Define custom rules for task notifications, status transitions, and escalation flows.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.53qvutjq7zf4"></a>Reporting &amp; Dashboards</h2><ul><li>Develop dashboards for leads, projects, and tasks with real-time filters.</li><li>Create exportable reports (CSV/PDF) for performance tracking.</li><li>Schedule automated email reports for project and team performance summaries.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.pdhb1hs7hv2o"></a>User Management &amp; Access Control</h2><ul><li>Define user roles and permissions: Admin, Project Manager, Team Member, External Collaborator.</li><li>Implement project-specific sharing with secure links and audit tracking.</li><li>Restrict visibility and edit access based on role and project association.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.3rp4t95qofma"></a>Audit Trail &amp; Logging</h2><ul><li>Maintain full activity logs for task changes, file uploads, and user actions.</li><li>Include a visible activity feed per project.</li><li>Provide admin-level access to filtered log data for auditing.</li></ul><h2><a id="_heading=h.12otb6m2ba0w"></a>Integrations (Optional)</h2><ul><li>Integrate with email services (Gmail/Outlook) for lead communication history.</li><li>Integrate messaging platforms (Slack/WhatsApp) for real-time task alerts.</li><li>Enable syncing with cloud storage services (Google Drive, Dropbox) for files.<a id="_heading=h.wxq3ov8iht6q"></a></li></ul>
